Kishel's, Judge Gregory F. Collection of Mesaba Airlines' Chapter 11 Bankruptcy Case Records 7000
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Judge Gregory F. Kishel's Collection of Mesaba Airlines' Chapter 11 Bankruptcy Case Records
2004-2007
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Kishel, Gregory F.
Kishel, Gregory F., 1946-
7000
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
This collection consists of the judicial decisions and illustrative documents from the Chapter 11 bankruptcy cases of Mesaba Airlines, Delta Airlines, and Northwest Airlines in the United States Bankruptcy and District Courts. It also includes local Minnesota press coverage on the Mesaba Airlines case.
10632550
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
E. Parker, July 18, 2019
EAD encoding:
Elizabeth Parker, July 18, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Gregory F. Kishel was a judge of the U.S. Bankruptcy Court for the District of Minnesota. Judge Kishel retired from the bench on May 31, 2016. He was first appointed as a part-time judge on May 24, 1984, and was appointed as a full- time judge on October 1, 1986. He was reappointed to 14-year terms in 2000 and 2014. He served as chief judge from October 1, 2000, to September 24, 2007, and again from January 31, 2011, to May 31, 2016.
Judge Kishel earned a bachelor's degree from Cornell University in 1973, and a J.D. from Boston College School of Law in 1977.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Bankruptcy -- United States.; Corporate reorganizations -- United States.; Mesaba Airlines; Northwest Airlines Corporation; Delta Air Lines
10632550
- Order Denying Debtor's Motion for Authority to Reject Collective Bargaining Agreements (May 18,2006) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Order on Remand, Re: Debtor's Renewed Motion for Authority to Reject Collective Bargaining Agreements (September 22,2006) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Memorandum of Law & Order - Civil File No. 06-3041 (MJD) - District of Minnesota (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Memorandum of Law Opposing Remand - Civ. No. 06-4320 and 06-4499, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- ALPA Exhibit 101: Airline Industry may topple labor groups (December 21,2004) - by Eric Torbenson /The Dallas Morning News (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bankruptcy Court Decisions (May30,2006) - Vol. 46, Iss 13 p. 2-3 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- NWA drops SkyTeam request; Mesaba may cut fleet by half by Joshua Freed - St. Paul Pioneer Press - (01/12/2006) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bankruptcy judge orders Northwest to pay Mesaba $5.2 million by USA TODAY (2005) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- NWA plans a new airline by Martin J. Moylan - Pioneer Press (Jan5,2006) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Judge blocks strike at Northwest by Chris Isidore - CNN Money - (August25,2006) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- MAIR executive testifies in bankruptcy case by Liz Fedor - Star Tribune (March 20,2006) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- ALPA News - Mesaba Pilots Vindicated by Bankruptcy Court Ruling (May 18,2006) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Mesaba pleas for sacrifice by Liz Fedor - Star Tribune (September7,2006) (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Small-jet pilots reject management demands to choose between jobs and concessions. By Gavin Francis, Staff Writer - January 2006 Air Line Pilot (Box 1, Folder 14)
- In Re: Northwest Airlines Corporation, et al., Debtors. - Chapter 11 Case No. 05-17930 (ALG) (November 9,2005) (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Declaration of John Spanjers - Case No. 05-39258 GJK - Chapter 11 (October 13,2005) (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Online News Printout about Mesaba (2006) (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Exhibit 506: "Evidenciary Presentation": Mesaba Aviation, Inc. - (February 17,2006) (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Order Granting Preliminary Injunction in Favor of Plaintiff (October 23,2006) (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Bankruptcy No.05 B 17923 (ASH). Adversary No. 06-1964A (February 7,2007) - Westlaw (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Correspondence between Gregory F. Kishel and Leonard, O'Brien Spencer, Gale & Sayre, LTD. (April 27,2006) (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Decision on Second Motion to Reject Collective Bargaining Agreement - Delta Air Lines No. 05 B 17923 (ASH) - (July21,2006) - Source Thomson/West (Box 1, Folder 22)
- In re: Northwest Airlines Corporation, et al., Debtors. Chapter 11 Case No. 05-17930 (ALG) - Memorandum of Opinion (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Decision and Order - Chapter 11 Case No. 05-17930 (ALG) - Victor Marrero, United States District Judge (2006) (Box 1, Folder 24)
- United States Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit - August Term 2006 - Docket Nos. 06-4371-cv(L), 06-4468-cv(CON) (Box 1, Folder 25)